(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(SCREAMING)
Doc!
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING)
Doc! Doc! Doc!
Doc! Doc!
What?
(SCREAMS)
Okay, relax, Doc.
It's me. It's me!
It's Marty.
No, it can't be.
I just sent you
back to the future.
Yeah. No, I know.
You did send me
back to the future,
but I'm back.
I'm back
from the future.
Great Scott!
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
(DOC SNORING)
BUFFALO BOB SMITH ON TV:
Hey, kids, what time is it?
CHILDREN: Howdy Doody time!
(GASPS)
Great Scott!
CHILDREN: (SINGING)
It's Howdy Doody Time
Bob Smith and Howdy Do
Say Howdy Do to you
Howdy Doody time?
Date. Sunday,
November 13, 1955.
7:01 a.m.
Last night's
time travel experiment
was apparently
a complete success.
Lightning struck
the clock tower at
precisely 10:04 p.m.
Sending the necessary
1.21 gigawatts into
the time vehicle,
which vanished in
a brilliant flash
of light
leaving a pair of
fire trails behind.
I, therefore,
assume that Marty
and the time vehicle
were transported
forward through time
into the year 1985.
After that...
(GASPS) After that,
I can't recall
what happened.
In fact,
I don't even remember
how I got home.
Perhaps
the gigawatt discharge
coupled with the temporal
displacement field
generated by
the time vehicle
caused a disruption
of my own brain waves
resulting in a condition
of momentary amnesia.
Indeed, I now recall
that moments
after the time vehicle
disappeared
into the future,
(GASPS) I saw a vision
of Marty saying
he had come back
from the future.
Hey, Doc!
Undoubtedly,
this was some sort
of residual image...
Doc.
(SCREAMING)
(DISSONANT
ORGAN CHORD PLAYING)
Doc, calm down, okay.
Just calm down.
It's me. It's Marty.
No, it can't be you!
I sent you back
to the future!
That's right, Doc.
That's right,
but I came back again.
I came back
from the future.
Don't you
remember last night?
You fainted.
I brought you home.
This can't be happening!
You can't be here!
It doesn't make sense
for you to be here!
I refuse to even believe
that you are here!
Doc, I am here,
and it does make sense.
Look, I came back to
1955 again with you,
the you from 1985,
'cause we had to
get a book from Biff!
So once I got
the book back,
you, that is the you
from 1985,
were in the DeLorean,
and it got struck
by lightning,
and you got
sent back to 1885!
DOC: 1885?
It's a very
interesting story,
future boy,
but there's just
one little thing that
doesn't make sense.
If the me of the future
is now in the past,
how could you
possibly know about it?
You sent me a letter.
"Dear Marty,
if my calculations
are correct,
"you will receive this
letter immediately after
"you saw the DeLorean
struck by lightning.
"First, let me assure you
that I'm alive and well.
"I've been living happily
these past eight months
in the year 1885.
"The lightning bolt
that hit the DeLorean
"caused a gigawatt
overload
"which scrambled
the time circuits,
"activated
the Flux Capacitor,
"and sent me
back to 1885.
"The overload shorted
out the time circuits
"and destroyed
the flying circuits.
"Unfortunately, the car
will never fly again."
It actually flew?
Yeah, we had
a hover conversion done
in the early
21st century.
Incredible!
"I set myself up
as a blacksmith
as a front
"while I attempted
to repair the damage
to the time circuits.
"Unfortunately,
this proved impossible,
"because suitable
replacement parts
"will not be
invented until 1947.
"However,
I've gotten quite adept
"at shoeing horses
and fixing wagons."
1885! Amazing!
I actually end up
as a blacksmith
in the Old West.
Pretty heavy, huh?
"I have buried the DeLorean
in the abandoned Delgado Mine
"adjacent to the old
Boot Hill Cemetery
"as shown on
the enclosed map.
"Hopefully, it should
remain undisturbed
"and preserved until
you uncover it in 1955.
"Inside, you will find
repair instructions.
"My 1955 counterpart..."
That's me.
"...should have no
problem repairing it
"so that you can drive it
back to the future.
"Once you have
returned to 1985,
destroy the time machine."
Destroy it?
Yeah. Well, it's
a long story, Doc.
"Do not, I repeat,
do not attempt
"to come back here
to get me.
"I am perfectly happy
living in the fresh air
and wide-open spaces.
"And I fear that
unnecessary time travel
"only risks
further disruption
"of the space-time
continuum.
"And please take care
of Einstein for me."
Einstein?
He's your dog, Doc.
Einstein is what you
call your dog in 1985.
(SCOFFS)
"I know you will
give him a good home.
"Remember to
walk him twice a day
"and that he only
likes canned dog food.
"These are my wishes.
Please respect them
and follow them.
"And so, Marty,
I now say farewell
and wish you Godspeed.
"You've been a good, kind,
and loyal friend to me,
"and you made a real
difference in my life.
"I will always treasure
our relationship
"and think on you
with fond memories,
"warm feelings,
and a special place
in my heart.
"Your friend in time,
Doc Emmett L. Brown.
"September 1st, 1885."
I never knew I could
write anything so touching.
I know. I know, Doc.
It's beautiful.
(WHIMPERING)
It's all right,
Copernicus.
Everything is
gonna be fine.
I'm sorry, Doc.
It's all my fault
you're stuck back there.
I never should've
let Biff get to me.
There are plenty
worse places to be
than the Old West.
I could have ended up
in the Dark Ages.
They probably
would have burned me
at the stake as
a heretic or something.
Let's look at the map.
All right,
according to this,
the time vehicle
is sealed off
in a side tunnel.
We may have to blast.
Whoa!
I think you woke up
the dead with that blast.
Take this camera.
I want to document
everything!
DOC: This reminds me
of the time
I attempted to reach
the center of the Earth.
I'd been reading
my favorite author,
Jules Verne.
I spent weeks preparing
that expedition.
I didn't even
get this far.
Of course,
I was only 12
at the time.
You know,
it was the writings
of Jules Verne
that had a profound
effect on my life.
It was when I was 11
that I first read
Twenty Thousand
Leagues Under the Sea.
It was then
that I realized
that I must devote
my life to science.
Doc, check it out.
Look at this.
My initials!
Just like in
Journey to the Center
of the Earth!
That means
the time machine
must be right
through this wall!
(SHUTTER CLICKS)
(SIGHS) It's been buried in
here for 70 years,
two months, and 13 days.
Astounding!
MARTY: "As you see,
the lightning bolt
"shorted out
the time circuit
control microchip.
"The attached..."
Schematic.
"Schematic diagram
will allow you to build
a replacement unit
"with 1955 components,
"thus restoring
the time machine to
perfect working order."
Unbelievable that
this little piece
of junk
could be
such a big problem.
No wonder this
circuit failed.
It says,
"Made in Japan."
What do you mean, Doc?
All the best stuff
is made in Japan.
Unbelievable!
(GEARS ENGAGING)
(MOTOR WHIRRING)
You know,
when I was a kid,
I always wanted
to be a cowboy.
And now,
knowing I'm gonna spend
my future in the past,
it sounds like
a wonderful way to spend
my retirement years.
It just
occurred to me, Marty,
since I end up in 1885,
perhaps I'm now in
the history books.
I wonder.
Could I go to
the library and
look myself up
in the old
newspaper archives?
I don't know, Doc.
You're the one
that's always saying,
you know,
it's not good
to know too much
about your own destiny.
You're right, Marty.
I know too much already.
Better that I not
attempt to uncover
the circumstances
of my own future.
Copernicus.
Come on, boy!
I'll get him, Doc.
Copernicus!
Copernicus, come on.
Let's go home, boy.
What's wrong?
What's wrong,
Copernicus? Come on.
Come on, let's go home.
Come on. Come on.
(COPERNICUS WHIMPERING)
Doc! Doc!
Come here!
Quick!
What's wrong, Marty?
You look like
you've seen a ghost.
You're not
far off, Doc.
Great Scott!
Check this out.
"Died September 7th,
1885."
That's one week after
you wrote the letter!
"Erected in
eternal memory
by his beloved Clara."
Who the hell
is Clara?
Marty, please
don't stand there!
Oh! Right. Sorry.
I gotta get
another picture.
DOC: "Shot in the back
by Buford Tannen
over a matter of $80"?
What kind of a future
do you call that?
MARTY: "Buford Tannen
was a notorious gunman
"whose short temper
and a tendency to drool
"earned him
the nickname Mad Dog.
"He was quick
on the trigger
"and bragged that
he had killed 12 men
"not including
Indians or Chinamen."
Does it mention me?
Am I one of the 12?
Just a minute.
"However this claim
cannot be substantiated,
"since precise records
were not kept
"after Tannen shot
a newspaper editor
"who printed
an unfavorable story
about him in 1884."
That's why
we can't find anything.
DOC: Look.
William McFly and family.
Your relatives?
MARTY:
My great-grandfather's
name was William.
That's him.
Good-looking guy.
McFlys, but no Browns.
Well, maybe it was
a mistake, Doc.
Maybe that grave
wasn't yours.
There could've been
another Emmett Brown
back in 1885.
No.
I don't know.
Did you have any
relatives here back then?
The Browns didn't
come to Hill Valley
until 1908.
And then they
were the von Brauns.
My father changed our name
during the First World War.
Doc, look.
(GASPS)
Great Scott, it's me!
Then it is true,
all of it.
It is me who
goes back there
and gets shot.
It's not gonna
happen, Doc.
After you fix
the time circuits
and put new tires
on the DeLorean,
I'm going back to 1885,
and I'm bringing you home.
The clothes fit?
(AIR HISSING)
MARTY: Yeah, everything
except the boots, Doc.
They're kind of tight.
I don't know.
Are you sure this
stuff is authentic?
Of course. Haven't
you ever seen a Western?
Yeah, I have, Doc.
Clint Eastwood never wore
anything like this.
Clint who?
That's right.
You haven't
heard of him yet.
Marty, you have
to wear the boots.
You can't wear
those futuristic things
back in 1885.
You shouldn't
even be wearing them
here in 1955.
All right, Doc.
Look, as soon
as I get there,
I'll put them on.
I promise.
Okay. I think
we're about ready.
I put gas in the tank.
Your future clothes
are packed.
Just in case,
fresh batteries for
your walkie-talkies.
Oh! What about that
floating device?
Hoverboard.
All right.
You know, Doc,
it's gonna be a hell
of a long walk
back to Hill Valley
from here.
It's still
the safest plan.
After all, we can't
risk sending you back
into a populated area
or to a spot that's
geographically unknown.
You don't want to
crash into some tree
that once existed
in the past.
This was all
completely open country,
so you'll have plenty
of run out space
when you arrive.
Remember,
where you're going,
there are no roads.
There's a small cave
over there
which will be
a perfect place to
hide the time vehicle.
Well, the new time
circuit control tubes
are warmed up.
(DEVICE BEEPING)
Time circuits on.
I wrote the letter
on September 1st,
so we'll send you back
the very next day,
September 2nd.
That's a Wednesday.
September 2nd,
1885, 8:00 a.m.
I get shot
on Monday the 7th,
so you have five days
to locate me.
According to my letter,
I'm a blacksmith,
so I probably have
a shop somewhere.
All you have to do is
drive the time vehicle
directly toward
that screen,
accelerating to
88 miles an hour.
Wait a minute.
Doc, if I drive straight
towards the screen,
I'm gonna crash
into those Indians.
Marty,
you're not thinking
fourth-dimensionally.
You'll instantly be
transported to 1885,
and those Indians
won't even be there.
Right.
Well.
Good luck for
both of our sakes.
See you in the future.
You mean the past.
Exactly.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Happy trails, Marty!
(ENGINE REVVING)
Ready, Marty?
Ready!
Set!
Hi-ho, Silver.
(ENGINE REVVING)
(EXCLAIMING IN SPANISH)
(ENGINE ACCELERATING)
(ALL WHOOPING)
Indians!
(SCREAMS)
The cave!
(FAINT RUMBLING)
MAN: Charge!
(BUGLE BLOWING)
Shit! The cavalry!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(SIGHS)
(SIGHS IN RELIEF)
(LIQUID TRICKLING)
(SNIFFING)
Damn, I ripped
the fuel line.
(BEAR GROWLING)
(EXCLAIMS)
(SCREAMING)
(GROWLING)
(SCREAMS)
(GRUNTING)
(GROANS)
(IN IRISH ACCENT) Maggie!
Fetch some water!
We got a hurt man here.
(GASPS)
Mom! Mom, is that you?
(IN IRISH ACCENT)
There, there now.
You've been asleep for
nearly six hours now.
I had this
horrible nightmare.
I dreamed...
I dreamed I was
in a Western.
I was being chased
by all these Indians
and a bear.
Well, you're safe
and sound
here now
at the McFly farm.
McFly farm?
(EXCLAIMS)
(PANTING)
Well, you're my...
You're my, my...
Who are you?
The name is McFly.
Maggie McFly.
McFly. Maggie?
And that's Mrs. McFly,
and don't you be
forgetting the Mrs.
And what might
your name be, sir?
Well, it's...
Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood.
Well, you hit your head,
Mr. Eastwood.
Not too serious,
but lucky for you,
Seamus found you
when he did.
Seamus.
Me husband.
(BABY COOING)
You'll be excusing me,
Mr. Eastwood,
while I tend to William.
William.
(WILLIAM CRYING)
MAGGIE: Oh, that's okay, Will.
It's okay.
That's William?
Aye.
William Sean McFly,
the first of our family
to be born in America.
It's okay, Will.
This here is
Mr. Clint Eastwood
here visiting.
He surely likes you,
Mr. Eastwood.
Maggie.
I've got supper.
SEAMUS: I'm not one
to pry into a man's
personal affairs,
but exactly how is it
that you came to
be way out here
without a horse,
or boots, or a hat?
Well, my car...
Horse broke down,
and a bear ate my boots,
and I guess
I just forgot my hat.
How could you forget
a thing like your hat?
Would you like
some water?
Yeah.
I'll tell you what
I'll do, Mr. Eastwood.
I'll help you find
your blacksmith friend.
You can stay
the night in the barn,
and tomorrow
I'll take you as far
as the railroad tracks.
You can follow them
straight on into town.
I'll even
give you a hat.
(SIGHS IN DISGUST)
That's great. Thanks.
(WILLIAM CRYING)
SEAMUS: Ah...
That's my William.
(COOING)
Oh.
Yes.
I think you'll find
the barn comfortable.
Never had any
complaints about it
from the pigs.
Mmm.
MAGGIE: Seamus!
A word with you.
Aye.
Will you hold him
for a minute?
(WILLIAM CRYING)
Are you sure
you're not after bringing
a curse on this house
taking him in
like that?
(SIGHS)
He's such
a strange young man.
Aye. But I've just
got a feeling
about him, Maggie,
that looking after him
is the right thing to do.
That it's important.
MARTY: Hey, buddy.
Look how the baby
takes to him.
Little Will never
takes to strangers.
It's almost as if
he's connected to us.
Hey, Will.
So you're my
great-grandfather.
The first McFly
born in America.
(URINATING)
And you peed on me.
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
(WHISTLES)
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(CHICKEN CLUCKING)
Give us some soap.
Here you go.
(DONKEY BRAYING)
(HAMMERING)
(WHIP CRACKING)
(URGING HORSE)
(EXCLAIMS)
Take a look and see
what just breezed
in the door.
Why, I didn't know
the circus was in town.
Must have
got that shirt
off a dead Chinese.
(MEN LAUGHING)
What will it be,
stranger?
I'll have ice water.
Ice water?
(MEN LAUGHING)
Water?
You want water,
you better go
dunk your head
in the horse trough
out there.
(MEN LAUGHING)
In here,
we pour whiskey.
Excuse me.
For what?
I'm trying to
find the blacksmith.
BUFORD: Hey, McFly!
Thought I done told
you never to come in...
You ain't
Seamus McFly.
You look like him,
though,
especially with
that dog-ugly hat.
(THUGS LAUGHING)
You kin to
that hay barber?
What's your name,
dude?
Marty...
Eastwood.
Clint Eastwood.
(LAUGHING)
What kind of
stupid name is that?
I'd say
he's the runt
of the litter.
Hey, now, boys,
would you take a look-see
at these pearly whites?
Hell, I ain't seen
teeth look that straight
that weren't
store-bought.
Take a gander at
them moccasins.
What kind of skins
is them?
What's that
writing mean?
"Nike"?
What is that?
Some sort of Injun
talk or something?
(ALL LAUGHING)
Bartender, I'm looking
for that no-good,
cheating blacksmith.
You seen him?
No, sir, Mr. Tannen.
I have not.
Tannen.
You're "Mad Dog" Tannen.
"Mad Dog"?
I hate that name.
I hate it, you hear?
Nobody calls me
"Mad Dog"!
Especially not
some duded-up,
egg-sucking gutter trash.
(EXCLAIMS)
Dance!
Come on!
(THUGS LAUGHING)
Come on, runt!
You can dance
better than that!
(LAUGHTER STOPS)
(MUTTERING RHYTHMICALLY)
Shit.
Whoo!
(EXCLAIMS IN DISGUST)
(CLICKING)
(GASPS)
You better run,
squirrel.
Get him!
(EXCLAIMS)
(WHINNYING)
Whoa!
(EXCLAIMING)
(THUG LAUGHING)
(GROANS)
(SCREAMS)
(THUGS WHOOPING)
(GUNSHOTS)
(SCREAMING)
(HORSE WHINNYING)
(THUGS LAUGHING)
We got ourselves
a new courthouse.
High time
we had a hanging!
(THUGS CHEERING)
(BUFORD EXCLAIMS)
(THUGS LAUGHING)
(THUGS SHOUTING)
(GRUNTING)
(THUGS WHOOPING)
THUG: Look at him swing.
(THUGS LAUGHING)
BUFORD: Yeah,
haven't had a hanging
in a long time!
It'll shoot the fleas
off a dog's back
at 500 yards, Tannen,
and it's pointed
straight at your head!
You owe me money,
blacksmith.
How do you figure?
My horse threw a shoe.
And seeing as
you was the one that
done the shoeing,
I say that makes
you responsible.
Well, since you never
paid me for the job,
I say that makes us even.
Wrong! See I was
on my horse
when it threw the shoe,
and I got throwed off!
And that caused me
to bust a perfectly
good bottle of
fine Kentucky red eye.
So the way
I figure it, blacksmith,
you owe me $5
for the whiskey
and $75 for the horse!
That's the $80.
Look, if your horse
threw a shoe,
bring him back,
and I'll reshoe him.
I done shot that horse!
Well, that's your problem,
Tannen.
Wrong. That's yours.
So from now on,
you better be looking
behind you when you walk.
Because one day
you're gonna get
a bullet in your back.
(ALL URGING HORSES)
Doc!
Marty, I gave you
explicit instructions
not to come here
but to go
directly back to 1985.
I know, Doc,
but I had to come.
But it's good to
see you, Marty.
Marty, you're gonna
have to do something
about those clothes.
You walk around town
dressed like that,
you're liable
to get shot.
Or hanged.
What idiot dressed you
in that outfit?
You did.
DOC: "Shot in the back
by Buford Tannen
"over a matter of $80,
"September 7"?
That's this Monday!
Now I wish
I'd paid him off.
And who's this
beloved Clara?
I don't know
anyone named Clara.
I don't know, Doc.
I thought maybe
she was a girlfriend
of yours.
Marty, my involvement
in such a social
relationship here in 1885
could result in
a disruption of the
space-time continuum.
As a scientist,
I can never
take that risk.
(STEAM HISSING)
Certainly not after
what we've already
been through.
HUBERT: Emmett!
Hello, Emmett.
DOC: Hubert.
It's the mayor.
Excuse me, Emmett.
Do you remember last week
at the town meeting
when you volunteered
to meet the new
schoolteacher
at the station
when she came in?
Oh, yes, quite so.
Well, we just got word
she's coming in tomorrow.
Here are the details
for you.
Thanks for
all your help.
Anytime, Hubert.
Oh!
Her name's Miss Clayton.
Clara Clayton.
Well, Doc,
now we know
who Clara is.
Marty, it's impossible.
The idea that I could
fall in love at first sight
is romantic nonsense.
(LAUGHS)
There's no
scientific rationale
for that concept.
Aw, come on, Doc.
It's not science.
You meet the right girl,
it just hits you.
It's like lightning.
Marty, please
don't say that.
That's the way it was
for me and Jennifer.
I mean,
we couldn't keep our
eyes off each other.
God, Jennifer, damn.
I hope she's
all right, Doc.
I can't believe
we just left her
there on the porch.
Don't worry, Marty.
She'll be fine.
When you burned
the almanac in 1955,
the normal timeline
was restored.
That means once
we're back in 1985,
you just have to
go over to her house
to wake her up.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
Oh, Marty,
turn that valve
over there
all the way
to the right.
Yeah, pull it
all the way around.
Okay. Let's go!
Iced tea?
No, thanks.
It's a refrigerator.
Well, I guess
Miss Clayton
will have to find
other transportation.
If I never
meet the woman,
there's no possibility
of a romantic
infatuation, right?
You're the doc, Doc.
All right.
We'll get the DeLorean
and get ourselves
back to the future.
Oh, listen, Doc,
I tore a hole
in the gas tank
when I was landing,
so we're gonna
have to patch it up
and get some gas.
You mean we're
out of gas?
Yeah, it's no big deal.
We've got
Mr. Fusion, right?
Mr. Fusion powers
the time circuits
and the Flux Capacitor,
but the internal
combustion engine runs
on ordinary gasoline.
It always has.
There's not gonna be
a gas station around here
until sometime in
the next century.
Without gasoline,
we can't get
the DeLorean up to
88 miles per hour.
So what do we do?
(DOC AND MARTY URGING HORSES)
(URGING HORSES)
Twenty-four!
It's no use, Marty!
Even the fastest
horse in the world
won't run more than 35,
40 miles an hour!
(DOC URGING HORSES)
MARTY: Bartender said
that's the strongest
stuff they got.
Try it, Marty.
(ENGINE TURNING)
(ENGINE SPUTTERING)
Give it more gas!
(ENGINE STOPS)
Damn!
(BOTH SIGH)
It blew the fuel
injection manifold.
Strong stuff,
all right.
It will take me a month
to rebuild it.
A month?
Doc, you're gonna
get shot on Monday!
I know! I know!
I know! I wish...
Wait. I've got it!
We can simply roll it
down a steep hill!
Oh! We'd never find
a smooth enough surface.
Unless...
Of course! Ice!
We'll wait until winter
when the lake freezes over.
Winter? Doc,
what are you
talking about?
Monday!
It's three days away!
All right, all right,
all right.
Just let's think
this thing through
logically.
We know it won't run
under its own power.
We know
we can't pull it.
But if we could
figure out a way
to push it up to
88 miles an hour.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Huh?
(BELL CLANGING)
(STEAM HISSING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
That's it.
How fast can she go?
Why, I've had her
up to 55 myself.
I heard that
Fearless Frank Fargo
got one of these
up to near 70
out past
Verde Junction.
Do you think it's
possible to get it
up to 90?
(SCOFFS) Ninety?
Tarnation, son,
who'd ever need to
be in such a hurry?
It's just a little bet
he and I have,
that's all.
Theoretically speaking,
could it be done?
Well, I suppose,
if you had a straight
stretch of track
with a level grade,
and you weren't
hauling no cars
behind you,
and if you could get
the fire hot enough.
And I'm talking about
hotter than the blazes of
hell and damnation itself.
Then yes, sir,
it might be possible
to get her up that fast.
Tell me, when
does the next train
come through here?
Monday morning at 8:00.
Here. This spur that
runs off the main line
three miles out
to Clayton Ravine.
It's a long stretch
of level track
that will still
exist in 1985.
This is where
we'll push the DeLorean
with the locomotive.
Funny. This map
calls Clayton Ravine
Shonash Ravine.
That must be the old
Indian name for it.
It's perfect.
A nice long run
that goes clear across
the bridge
over the ravine,
you know,
over near that Hilldale
housing development.
Right, Doc,
but according to this map,
there is no bridge.
Well, Doc,
we can scratch that idea.
I mean, we can't
wait a year and a half
for this thing
to get finished.
Marty, it's perfect.
You're just
not thinking
fourth-dimensionally.
Right. Right.
I have a real
problem with that.
Don't you see?
The bridge will
exist in 1985.
It's safe
and still in use.
Therefore, as long
as we get the DeLorean
up to 88 miles an hour
before we hit
the edge of the ravine,
we'll instantaneously
arrive at a point in time
where the bridge
is completed.
We'll have track under us
and coast safely
across the ravine.
What about
the locomotive?
It will be
a spectacular wreck.
Too bad no one will
be around to see it.
(CLARA SCREAMING)
Help me! Help!
Great Scott!
(HORSES NEIGHING)
(BOTH URGING HORSES)
(URGING HORSE)
Hurry!
Jump!
(EXCLAIMS)
DOC: Whoa.
Whoa.
Oh...
Thank you, sir.
You saved my...
...life.
Emmett Brown at
your service, Miss...
(STAMMERING)
Clayton.
Clara Clayton.
Clara!
What a beautiful name.
May I help you
inside with these?
Oh, no,
that won't be necessary.
I can take care of it.
You've done more
than enough already.
But it's really
no trouble.
Doc, she says it's fine,
and we got to get going.
Ma'am, good luck with
your school teaching
and everything.
Clara, I'll straighten
everything out
with Mr. Statler for
the buckboard rental.
Don't worry about that.
I feel
somewhat responsible
for what happened.
Oh.
That would be very
gentlemanly of you,
Mr. Brown. Emmett.
You know,
I'm almost glad
that snake
spooked those horses.
Otherwise,
we might never have met.
I suppose
it was destiny.
Well, thank you
for everything.
You're quite welcome.
I will see you again,
won't I?
Of course.
You'll see lots of me.
I'm sure.
I have a shop in town.
I'm the local scientist,
(STAMMERING) blacksmith.
Science?
What sort of science?
Astronomy?
Chemistry?
Actually, I'm a student
of all sciences.
Hey, Doc,
we got to get going.
Oh, yes.
Well, excuse us, Clara.
We have to get going.
Toodle-oo.
What do you mean,
you're gonna be
seeing lots of her, Doc?
Well, I might see her
again just in passing.
Come on, Doc.
Did you see the way
she was looking at you?
(CHUCKLES)
She did have
quite a scare, right?
After all, Miss Clayton
almost ended up
at the bottom of
Clayton Ravine.
Holy shit. Hey, Doc,
Clayton Ravine was
named after a teacher.
They say she fell in
there 100 years ago.
100 years ago!
That's this year!
Every kid in school
knows that story,
'cause we all
have teachers
we'd like to see
fall into the ravine.
Great Scott!
Then she was
supposed to go over
in that wagon.
Now I may have
seriously altered history.
Look, Doc,
what's the worst
that can happen, huh?
So they don't name
the ravine after her.
Let's just get
the DeLorean ready
and get the hell
out of here.
I wish I'd never invented
that infernal time machine.
It's caused
nothing but disaster.
Doc, Doc,
this is Marty.
Do you read me? Over.
Check, Marty.
Great, Doc.
These things still work.
All right, Marty.
Once more, let's go over
the entire plan and layout.
I apologize for the
crudity of this model,
but I just...
Yeah, I know, Doc.
It's not to scale.
It's okay, Doc.
All right.
Tomorrow night, Sunday,
we'll load the DeLorean
onto the tracks here,
on the spur
right by the old
abandoned silver mine.
The switch track is
where the spur runs
off the main line
three miles
out to Clayton...
Shonash Ravine.
The train leaves
the station at 8:00
Monday morning.
We'll stop it here,
uncouple the cars
from the tender,
throw the switch track,
and then we'll hijack...
Borrow the locomotive
and use it to push
the time machine.
According to
my calculations,
we'll reach
88 miles per hour
just before we hit
the edge of the ravine,
at which point
we'll be instantaneously
transported back to 1985
and coast safely across
the completed bridge.
What does this mean?
"Point of no return."
That's our
fail-safe point.
Up until there,
we have still
have enough time
to stop the locomotive
before it plunges
into the ravine.
But once we
pass this windmill,
it's the future
or bust.
Here you go, Marty.
Connect that to
the positive terminal.
All right,
Marty, you all set?
Yeah. Yeah. Go!
(BELL DINGING)
DOC: Train pulling
out of the station!
Coming up to
the switch track!
Stop at
Throw the switch!
Pull up
to the DeLorean!
Pushing the DeLorean
up to 88 miles per hour!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
It couldn't be simpler.
(DOOR OPENS)
CLARA: Emmett?
It's Clara.
Quick,
cover the DeLorean!
Hello.
Why, hello.
This is
quite a surprise.
Well, I hope I'm not
disturbing anything.
Oh, no, no, we were
just doing a little
model railroading.
Oh.
Emmett, when
my bags were thrown
from the wagon,
my telescope
was damaged.
And since you mentioned
an interest in science,
I thought
you might be able
to repair it for me.
I would pay you,
of course.
Oh, no, no, no.
I wouldn't think of
charging you for this.
Well, let's have
a look at it.
CLARA: I think a lens may
be out of alignment,
because if you
move it this way,
the image turns fuzzy.
See?
But if you turn it
the other way then...
Everything becomes...
...clear.
(CLEARS THROAT)
I could repair it right away
and have it for you tonight.
Oh, tonight is
the town festival.
I wouldn't dream of
having you work
on my telescope
during such
an important occasion.
You are planning
on attending,
aren't you?
Well, actually,
ma'am, I don't think...
Yes, of course,
the festival.
Well, in that case,
I'll see you this evening
at the festival, Emmett.
Mr. Eastwood.
Ma'am.
Thank you for
taking care of
my telescope.
You're quite welcome.
It's a nice telescope.
Ladies and gentlemen,
as mayor of Hill Valley,
it gives me great pleasure
to dedicate this clock
to the people
of Hill County!
(CROWD CHEERING)
May it stand
for all time!
Tell me when, gentlemen.
(DRUMROLL PLAYING)
ALL: Three! Two! One!
Now!
(BAND PLAYING UPLIFTING MUSIC)
Let the festivities
begin!
You know, Marty,
in a way, it's fitting
that you and I are
here to witness this.
It's too bad I didn't
bring my camera.
Ready, gentlemen?
The only problem is
we'll never be able
to show it to anybody.
Smile, Doc.
MAN: Yee-ha!
(UP-TEMPO COUNTRY
MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE WHOOPING)
What great music!
Yeah, it's got a beat,
and you can dance to it.
Step right up
gentlemen
and test your mettle
with the latest products
from Colonel Samuel
Colt's Patent Firearms
Manufacturing Company
of Hartford,
Connecticut.
(INAUDIBLE)
Now, take this model,
for example.
The new,
improved and refined
Colt Peacemaker
selling to you tonight
for the low,
low price of $12.
Good evening.
Evening.
You look very nice.
Thank you.
Would you like...
Would you care to...
I'd love to.
Young man, how about you?
You want to give it a try?
No, no. No, thanks.
Hey, Doc, this...
Son!
Sonny boy!
The Doc can dance?
Son. Son. Son!
Hey, I just told you
that even a baby could
handle this weapon.
Surely you're not
afraid to try something
that a baby could do.
Hey, I'm not afraid
of nothing.
Come on, then.
Let's just step
up here like a man.
Now, then what you do
is you just ease
that hammer back there
and squeeze off
a round.
No, no, no!
Right on out there
and be real smooth.
That's the way
you do it.
(LAUGHING)
Listen,
can I try that again?
Yeah, go ahead.
Hey, just tell me
one thing.
Where did you learn
to shoot like that?
7-Eleven.
Buford, you sure
that blacksmith
is gonna be at
this here shindig?
Sure he's here.
Everybody's here
tonight.
You gentlemen will have
to check your firearms
if you want to join in
on the festivities.
(THUGS LAUGHING)
Who's gonna make us,
tenderfoot? You?
(GUN COCKING)
STRICKLAND: I am.
BUFORD: Marshal Strickland.
I didn't know you
was back in town.
If you can't
read the sign, Tannen,
I presume
you can read this.
Pretty tough hombre
when you're pointing
a scatter gun
at a man's back.
Just like you, Tannen,
I take every advantage
I can get.
Now you gonna
check your iron?
I was just joking
with your deputy.
Of course,
I'm gonna check my iron.
We all were.
Weren't we, boys?
THUG: Yeah, right.
DEPUTY: Tannen.
Your knife, too.
Smile, Marshal.
After all,
this is a party.
Only party
I'll be smiling at
is the one that sees you
at the end of a rope.
Have fun!
See, that's how
you handle them, Son.
Never give them
an inch
and maintain discipline
at all times.
Remember that word,
discipline.
I will, Pa.
MAN: (SINGING)
Swing that partner
With a right big swing
Over to the side
It's the same old thing
Thank you very much.
Why, Mr. Eastwood,
nice to see you.
I see you got yourself
some respectable clothes,
lad, and a fine hat.
Yeah, well,
a couple people
didn't like the way
the other one
looked on me.
Sure, and that one
suits you, Mr. Eastwood.
It's very becoming.
Oh, thanks.
Hey, "Frisbie."
Far out.
What was the meaning
of that?
It was right
in front of him.
Aye.
MAN: (SINGING)
Swing that partner
halfway round
Sashay back to
the head of the set
All the way up to
Now, bow to the partner
You're through
(CROWD CHEERING)
Hey, that's mine!
Not anymore.
Give me that.
There he is, Buford.
Where?
There.
Dancing with that
piece of calico.
THUG: What are you
gonna do, boss?
I figure if I bury
this muzzle
deep enough in his back,
nobody will hear the shot.
Careful, Buford.
You ain't got but one
bullet with that.
I only need one.
(SLOW COUNTRY MUSIC PLAYING)
I told you to watch
your back, smithy.
Tannen, you're early.
It's a Derringer, smithy.
Small but effective.
The last time I used it,
fellow took two whole
days to die.
Bled to death inside.
It was real,
real painful.
(THUGS LAUGHING)
That means you'll
be dead by about
supper time Monday.
Excuse me. I don't know
who you think you are,
but we're dancing.
Well, look at what
we have here.
Ain't you gonna
introduce me
to the lady?
I'd like a dance.
I wouldn't give
you the pleasure.
You'll just have to
go ahead and shoot.
All right.
No, no. Emmett,
I'll dance with him.
Boys, keep the
blacksmith company
while I get acquainted
with the filly!
(EXCLAIMING)
(LAUGHING)
I don't dance very well
when my partner has
a gun in his hand.
You'll learn.
You know, smithy,
maybe I'll just take
my $80 worth out of her!
Tannen,
leave her alone!
(THUGS LAUGHING)
(LAUGHING) Whoo!
Yeah, I bet there's
something you can do
that's worth $80.
I believe you've
underestimated me,
mister.
Have I?
(GROANS)
Ow!
(DOC GRUNTING)
Stop it!
Damn you, Tannen!
No, I damn you!
I damn you to hell!
(SIGHS)
You.
Hey, lighten up, jerk!
Mighty strong words,
runt!
You man enough
to back them up
with more than
just a pie plate?
Look, just leave
my friends alone.
What's wrong, dude?
You yellow?
(LAUGHING)
That's what I thought.
A yellow belly.
Nobody calls me yellow.
Then let's
finish it right now.
Not now, Buford.
Marshal's got our guns.
Like I said,
we'll finish this tomorrow!
Tomorrow we're robbing
the Pine City stage.
What about Monday?
We doing anything Monday?
No, Monday would be fine.
You can kill him on Monday.
I'll be back
this way on Monday.
We'll settle this then.
Right there
out in the street
in front of
the Palace Saloon.
Yeah, right. When?
High noon?
Noon?
I do my killing
before breakfast. 7:00!
8:00. I do my killing
after breakfast.
DOC: (WHISPERS) Marty!
(MOUTHING)
(CRYING)
(GUN COCKING)
STRICKLAND:
All right, now.
Break it up.
What's all this about?
You causing
trouble here, Tannen?
No trouble, Marshal.
Just a little personal matter
between me and Eastwood.
This don't
concern the law.
Tonight, everything
concerns the law.
Now break it up.
Any brawling,
it's 15 days
in the county jail.
All right, folks.
Come on, this is a party.
Come on!
Let's have some fun!
(CROWD CHEERING)
(UP-TEMPO COUNTRY
MUSIC PLAYING)
8:00 Monday, runt.
If you ain't here,
I'll hunt you
and shoot you down
like a duck.
It's "dog," Buford.
Shoot him down
like a dog.
Let's go, boys!
Let these sissies
have their party!
Marty,
what are you doing,
saying you're
gonna meet Tannen?
Hey, Doc, Doc,
don't worry about it.
Monday morning 8:00 a.m.
We're gonna
be gone, right?
Theoretically, yes,
but what if
the train's late?
Late?
We'll discuss
this later.
No, we'll discuss it now.
Late? What do you mean?
Thank you for
your gallantry,
Mr. Eastwood.
Hey, ma'am.
Had you not interceded,
Emmett might have
been shot.
Marty...
Clint, I'm gonna
take Clara home.
Right.
Good night, Doc.
Good night, Clara.
You sure set him straight,
Mr. Eastwood.
I'm glad somebody
finally got the gumption
to stand up to
that son of a bitch.
You're all right in
my book, Mr. Eastwood.
I'd like to
buy you a drink.
Hey, listen,
I don't want a drink.
You don't have to
buy me anything.
Young man. Young man.
It was no big deal.
I'd like for you to
have this brand-new
Colt Peacemaker
and gun belt
free of charge.
Free?
I want everybody
to know
that the gun that
shot Buford Tannen
was a Colt Peacemaker!
Hey, no problem.
Thanks a lot.
Of course
you understand
that if you lose,
I'm taking it back.
Thanks again.
You had him,
Mr. Eastwood.
You could have
just walked away,
and nobody
would have thought
the less of you for it.
All it would
have been was words,
hot air from a buffoon.
Instead,
you let him rile you.
Rile you into
playing his game,
his way, by his rules.
Seamus, relax.
I know what I'm doing.
He reminds me
of poor Martin.
Aye.
Who?
Me brother.
Wait a minute.
You have a brother
named Martin McFly?
Had a brother.
Martin used to
let men provoke him
into fighting.
He was concerned that
people would think him
a coward if he refused.
That's how he got
a Bowie knife shoved
through his belly
in a saloon
in Virginia City.
Never considered
the future, poor Martin.
God rest his soul.
Sure, and I hope
you're considering
the future, Mr. Eastwood.
I think about it
all the time.
CLARA: And that crater
in the middle north west,
the one that's
out there all by itself
like a starburst...
DOC: Uh-huh.
...that one's
called Copernicus.
Listen to me.
I feel like I'm
teaching school.
(LAUGHING)
Please,
continue the lesson.
I never found
lunar geography
so fascinating.
You're quite
knowledgeable.
When I was 11,
I had diphtheria.
I was quarantined
for three months.
So my father
brought this telescope,
and he put it
next to my bed
so I could
see everything
out the window.
(SIGHS)
Emmett, do you think
we'll ever be able
to travel to the moon
the way we travel
across the country
on trains?
Definitely.
Although not for 84 years
and not on trains.
We'll have
space vehicles, capsules
sent aloft with rockets.
Devices that
create giant explosions.
Explosions so powerful
that they just...
That they break the pull
of the Earth's gravity
and send the projectile
through outer space.
Emmett,
I read that book, too!
You're quoting
Jules Verne
From the Earth
to the Moon.
You've read Jules Verne?
I adore Jules Verne.
So do I.
Twenty Thousand
Leagues Under the Sea.
My absolute favorite.
The first time
I read that when
I was a little boy,
why, I wanted to
meet Captain Nemo.
Don't tease, Emmett.
You couldn't have
read that when
you were a boy.
It was only first
published 10 years ago.
Oh, yes. Well,
I meant it made me
feel like a boy.
I never met a woman
who liked Jules Verne
before.
I never ever met a man
like you before.
(CUCKOOING)
(BELL RINGS)
(HEN CLUCKING)
(SIZZLING)
(ROOSTER CROWING)
(MARTY GROANING)
Doc?
Hope you know
what you're doing.
You talking to me?
You talking to me,
Tannen?
Well, I'm the
only one here.
Go ahead,
make my day.
Say good morning,
Mr. Eastwood.
Morning.
Have a cigar,
Mr. Eastwood.
Anything I can
do for you today,
Mr. Eastwood?
No, that's fine.
Good luck tomorrow,
Mr. Eastwood.
We'll be praying
for you.
Thanks.
Good morning,
Mr. Eastwood.
Interest you
in a new suit
for tomorrow?
I'm fine. Thanks.
(SNIFFING)
Doc, what are
you doing?
Oh, nothing.
I was just out
enjoying the morning air.
It's really lovely here
in the morning.
Don't you think?
Yeah, it's lovely, Doc.
So listen, we've got
to load the DeLorean up
and get ready
to roll, all right?
Hey, look at that,
the tombstone.
Marty, let me see
that photograph again.
(GASPS) My name,
it's vanished.
Hey, that's great, Doc.
Don't you get it?
We're going back to
the future tomorrow,
so everything's
being erased.
But only my name
is erased.
The tombstone itself
and the date still remain.
That doesn't
make sense.
We know that this
photograph represents
what will happen
if the events
of today continue
to run their course
into tomorrow.
Right. So?
Excuse me,
Mr. Eastwood.
I just need to take
your measurements.
Oh, look, pal,
I don't want
to buy a suit.
(CHUCKLES)
No, this is
for your coffin.
My coffin?
Well, the odds are
running two to one
against you.
Might as well
be prepared.
So it may not be my name
that's supposed to end up
on this tombstone.
It may be yours.
Great Scott.
I know.
This is heavy.
Marty, why are you
wearing that gun?
You're not considering
going up against
Tannen tomorrow?
Doc, tomorrow morning
I'm going back to
the future with you.
But if Buford Tannen
comes looking
for trouble,
I'm gonna be
ready for him.
You heard what
that son of a bitch
called me last night.
Marty, you can't go
losing your judgment
every time someone
calls you a name.
That's exactly
what causes you
to get into that accident
in the future.
What?
What about my future?
I can't tell you.
It might make
things worse.
Wait a minute.
Doc, what is wrong
with my future?
Marty,
we all have to
make decisions
that affect
the course of our lives.
You've got to do
what you've got to do,
and I've got to do
what I've got to do.
Marty.
Yeah.
I've made a decision.
Uh-huh.
I'm not going
with you tomorrow.
(CHUCKLES)
I'm staying here.
What are you
talking about, Doc?
There's no point
in denying it.
I'm in love with Clara.
Oh, man.
Doc,
we don't belong here.
Neither one of us.
You know,
it could still be you
that gets shot tomorrow.
This tombstone
could still be
in your future.
Marty, the future
isn't written.
It can be changed.
You know that.
Anyone can make
their future whatever
they want it to be.
I can't let this
one little photograph
determine
my entire destiny.
I have to
live my life
according to
what I believe is
right in my heart.
(SIGHS)
Doc, you're a scientist.
So you tell me.
What's the right thing
to do up here?
You're right, Marty.
(SIGHS)
Wow, that worked great.
I've at least got
to tell her goodbye.
Come on, Doc.
Think about it.
What are you
gonna say to her?
"I've got to go
back to the future?"
I mean,
she's not gonna
understand that, Doc.
Hell, I'm in it
with you,
and I don't
even understand it.
Doc, listen.
Maybe we...
I don't know,
maybe we can just
take Clara with us.
To the future?
As you reminded me,
Marty, I'm a scientist,
so I must be
scientific about this.
I cautioned you
about disrupting
the continuum
for your own
personal benefit.
Therefore,
I must do no less.
We shall proceed
as planned,
and as soon as
we return to 1985,
we'll destroy this
infernal machine.
Traveling through time
has become
much too painful.
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
It's Emmett, Clara.
Emmett,
won't you come in?
No, I better not. I...
What's wrong?
I've come
to say goodbye.
Goodbye? Well,
where are you going?
I'm going away.
And well, I'm afraid
I'll never see you again.
Emmett!
Clara, I want you
to know that I care
about you deeply.
But I've realized
that I don't
belong here,
and I have to go back
where I came from.
And where
might that be?
I can't tell you.
Well,
wherever you're going,
take me with you.
I can't, Clara.
I wish it didn't
have to be this way,
but just believe me
when I tell you
that I'll never forget you
and that I love you.
I don't understand
what you're trying
to say.
Clara, I don't think
there's any way that
you can understand it.
Please, Emmett.
Please, I have to know.
If you sincerely
do love me,
then tell me
the truth.
All right then.
I'm from the future.
I came here
in a time machine
that I invented,
and tomorrow
I have to go back
to the year 1985.
(SIGHS)
Yes, Emmett.
I do understand.
I understand that
because you know
I'm partial to
the writings
of Jules Verne,
you concocted
those mendacities
in order to take
advantage of me.
Oh! I've heard some
whoppers in my day,
but the fact
that you'd expect me
to entertain
a notion like that
is so insulting
and degrading!
All you had to say is,
"I don't love you,
"and I don't want
to see you anymore."
That, at least,
would have been
respectful!
But that's
not the truth.
(CLARA SOBBING)
(HONKY-TONK
PIANO MUSIC PLAYING)
(PEOPLE CHATTERING)
MAN: Good to
see you, too.
Emmett.
What can I get you?
The usual?
No, Chester,
I'm gonna need
something
a lot stronger
than that tonight.
Sarsaparilla.
Whiskey, Chester.
Whiskey?
Emmett, are you sure?
You know
what happened to you
on the Fourth of July.
Whiskey.
Okay, I ain't your papa.
Just don't
want to see you
do the wrong thing.
You can leave
the bottle.
It's a woman, right?
I knew it.
I have seen that look
on a man's face
a thousand times
all across the country.
All I can
tell you, friend,
is you'll get over her.
Oh... Clara was
one in a million.
One in a billion.
One in a googolplex.
The woman of my dreams,
and I've lost her
for all time.
I can assure you, sir,
there are other women.
Why,
peddling this barbed wire
all across the country
has taught me
one thing for certain,
is that you never know
what the future
might bring.
The future.
Oh, I can tell you
about the future.
(HORSE NEIGHING)
(GROANS)
Oh, man, did I sleep.
What time is it, Doc?
Doc?
BUFORD: Wake up!
(GROANS)
Get up! Let's go!
I got me
a runt to kill.
It's still early, boss.
What's your hurry?
I'm hungry.
And in the future,
we don't need horses.
We have
motorized carriages
called automobiles.
(LAUGHS)
If everybody's got
one of these
auto whatsits,
does anybody walk
or run anymore?
Of course we run,
but for recreation,
for fun.
Run for fun?
What the hell
kind of fun is that?
(MEN LAUGHING)
Doc! Doc!
How much
has he had?
None.
That's the first one,
and he hasn't
touched it yet.
He just likes
to hold it.
(MAN LAUGHING)
Doc! Doc!
What are you doing?
I've lost her, Marty.
There's nothing left
for me here.
All right,
that's why you gotta
come back with me.
Where?
Back to the future!
Right!
Let's get going!
Great.
Gentlemen, excuse me,
but my friend and I
have to catch a train.
(LAUGHING) Here's to you,
blacksmith.
And to the future.
Amen.
Emmett, no!
Doc! Doc! Doc!
Come on, Doc.
Wake up. Wake up, Doc!
How many did he have?
Just the one.
Just the one?
Come on, Doc.
There's a fellow that
can't hold his liquor.
Get me some coffee.
Black!
Joey, coffee!
(CLOCK BELL TOLLING)
(BUFORD URGING HORSE)
Ma'am?
How far does
the 8:00 train go?
San Francisco is
the end of the line.
I'll take
a one-way ticket.
You want to
sober him up
in a hurry, son,
you're gonna have
to use something a lot
stronger than coffee.
Yeah,
what do you suggest?
Joey, let's make
some wake-up juice.
Come on, Doc, swallow.
Here we go.
In about 10 minutes,
he's gonna be as sober
as a priest on Sunday.
Ten minutes!
Why do we have to
cut these things
so damn close?
Here, stick this
clothespin on his nose.
When he opens up
his mouth,
go ahead
and pour it on
down his gullet.
Oh, and stand back.
(SCREAMING)
He's still out!
Oh, that? That was
just a reflex action.
It's gonna take
a few more minutes
for the stuff
to really clear up
his head.
Perfect.
(BELL CLANGING)
MARTY: Come on, Doc.
Come on, wake up, buddy.
Wake up, Doc!
Come on. Come on.
Seamus, wouldn't
expect to see you
here this morning.
Aye. Something
inside me told me
I should be here
as if my future
had something
to do with it.
He'll come around
in a minute. Come on.
Come on, Doc.
Let's go, Doc!
Let's wake up now, buddy.
Come on.
Are you in there,
Eastwood?
It's 8:00,
and I'm calling you out.
It's not 8:00 yet!
It is by my watch!
Let's settle this
once and for all, runt!
Or ain't you
got the gumption?
Listen.
I'm not really
feeling up to this
today.
So I'm gonna
have to forfeit.
Forfeit?
What's that mean?
It means that you win
without a fight.
Without shooting?
He can't do that.
Hey, you can't do that!
You know what I think?
I think you ain't
nothing but a gutless,
yellow turd!
And I'm giving you
to the count of 10
to come out here
and prove I'm wrong!
One!
Doc, come on,
sober up, buddy.
Let's go. Come on.
Two!
MAN: You better get
out there, son.
I got
$20 gold bet on you,
so don't let me down.
Three!
I got
$30 gold bet against you,
so don't let me down.
Four!
You better face
up to it, son,
because if you
don't go out there...
What?
Five!
What if I don't
go out there?
You're a coward.
Six!
And you'll be
branded a coward for
the rest of your days!
Everybody everywhere
will say Clint Eastwood
is the biggest
yellow belly
in the West!
Seven!
Here!
BUFORD: Eight!
I already got a gun.
BUFORD: Nine!
Ten!
Do you hear me, runt?
I said that's 10,
you gutless,
yellow pie-slinger!
He's an asshole!
I don't care
what Tannen says!
And I don't care
what anybody else
says either.
Doc! Doc, you okay?
I think so.
(GROANS)
What a headache!
Listen, you got
a back door
to this place?
Yeah, it's in the back.
Let's go, Doc.
Are you coming out here,
or do I have to
come in after you?
The thing I really
miss here is Tylenol.
Hey!
(GROANING)
(GUNS FIRING)
Reach, blacksmith!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(BELL CLANGING)
MAN: Yes, sir,
that poor fellow
last night
had the worst case
of broken heart
I have ever seen.
When he said
he didn't know
how he could live
the rest of his life
knowing how much hurt
he'd caused
that little girl.
Well,
I really felt for him.
I did. Right here.
BUFORD:
Listen up, Eastwood!
I aim to shoot
somebody today,
and I prefer
it'd be you.
But if you're
just too damn yellow,
I guess it'll
just have to be
your blacksmith friend.
Forget about me, Marty,
and save yourself!
You got one minute
to decide.
You hear me, runt?
One minute!
I've never seen
a man so broken up
over a woman.
What did he say
her name was?
Cara? Sara?
Clara.
(GASPS)
Excuse me.
Ma'am?
But was this man tall
with great big,
brown puppy-dog eyes
and long silvery,
flowing hair?
You know him.
(SIGHS)
Emmett!
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
(ALL EXCLAIMING)
Time's up, runt!
(CLOCK BELL TOLLING)
Prepare to meet
your maker, blacksmith.
Right here, Tannen!
Draw!
No!
I thought we could
settle this like men.
You thought wrong, dude.
(CROWD GASPING)
(LAUGHING)
Thank you.
(GASPS)
(SCREAMING)
(YELLING)
(YELLS)
(CROWD LAUGHING)
(LAUGHS)
That was good.
You know
what I think?
No.
I think Buford's
going to jail.
Yeah.
(GROANS)
Get him out
of that shit.
Get them!
Buford Tannen,
you're under arrest
for robbing
the Pine City stage.
You got anything to say?
I hate manure.
Look!
Yes!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
The train!
Can we make it?
We'll have to
cut them off
at Coyote Pass.
Hey! Hey, mister.
Mr. Eastwood.
Here's your gun, mister.
Thanks, kid.
Seamus!
It's worth $12.
Never been used.
Maybe I'll trade it
for a new hat.
Right,
and take care
of that baby!
I will!
Emmett!
(PANTING)
"Time machine."
(URGING HORSE)
(GRUNTING)
Come on, Marty!
(URGING HORSE)
Go, Doc.
Come on.
Give me your hand!
(BOTH GRUNTING)
(GRUNTS)
Come on, Marty.
(SCREAMING)
Come on. Let's go!
Masks on.
(GUN COCKING)
Reach!
Is this a holdup?
It's a science experiment.
Stop the train
just before you hit
the switch track up ahead.
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
Doc!
Uncouple the cars
from the tender!
(WHISTLE BLOWING)
I've wanted to
do that all my life.
(LAUGHING)
(BRAKES SCREECHING)
What are these things,
anyway?
My own version
of Pres-to-Logs.
Compressed wood
with anthracite dust
chemically treated to
burn hotter and longer.
I use them in my forge
so I don't have to stoke it.
These three in the furnace
will ignite sequentially,
make the fire
burn hotter,
kick up
the boiler pressure,
and make the train
go faster.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(URGING HORSE)
Ready to roll!
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Emmett!
Marty, are the
time circuits on?
(BEEPS)
Check, Doc!
Input the destination time.
October 27, 1985,
11:00 a.m.
Check. Okay,
we're cruising at a steady
25 miles an hour, Doc.
DOC: I'm throwing in
the Pres-to-Logs.
Marty, the new gauge
on the dashboard
will tell us
the boiler temperature.
It's color-coded
to indicate when
each log will fire.
Green, yellow and red.
Each detonation
will be accompanied
by a sudden burst
of acceleration.
(URGING HORSE)
Hopefully, we'll hit
88 miles per hour
before the needle
gets much past 2,000.
Why? What happens
after it hits 2,000?
The whole boiler
explodes!
Perfect!
(GASPS)
Hey, Doc!
We just hit 35!
Okay, Marty.
I'm coming aboard!
Emmett!
Come on. Come on.
You better hold
onto something, Doc!
The yellow log
is about to blow!
(BOTH EXCLAIMING)
Golly.
We just passed 40, Doc!
Emmett!
We just passed 45, Doc!
Go for it!
Fifty.
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
Emmett!
Clara!
I love you!
Doc! Doc!
What's happening?
It's Clara!
She's on the train!
Clara? Perfect.
She's in the cab!
I'm going back for her!
The windmill!
Doc! The windmill!
We're going past 50!
You'll never make it!
Then we'll have to
take her back with us!
Keep calling out
the speed!
Clara,
climb out here to me!
I don't know if I can!
You can do it!
Just don't look down!
That's it!
Sixty miles
an hour, Doc!
You're doing fine!
Nice and steady!
Come on!
Just a little further!
I can't, Emmett!
I'm scared!
Seventy!
Keep coming, Clara!
Come on! Come on!
You're doing fine!
Come on!
Nice and easy!
Don't look down!
That's it!
You're doing fine!
Doc! The red log
is about to blow!
(SCREAMING)
Clara!
(EXCLAIMING)
Emmett!
(SCREECHING)
I'm trying
to reach you!
Clara, hold on!
I can't!
Oh!
Doc, I'm gonna slip you
the Hoverboard!
Marty, watch out!
(SCREAMING)
Emmett, help!
Hold on, Clara!
(EXCLAIMS)
Doc, ready, Doc?
Catch it!
Yes! Yes!
Emmett!
Hold on!
(SCREAMING)
Yes!
(TRAIN CROSSING BELL CLANGING)
(HELICOPTER WHIRRING)
(CAR HORN HONKING)
(TRAIN WHISTLE BLOWING)
(ELECTRICAL BUZZING)
(BUZZING STOPS)
Well, Doc,
it's destroyed.
Just like you wanted.
(PANTING)
Hey, butthead,
get away...
Watch it, Biff!
Marty, I didn't mean
to scare you.
I didn't recognize you
in those clothes.
What the hell
are you doing?
Just putting on
the second coat now.
You going cowboy, huh?
Come on, guys.
We're gonna be
late for brunch.
OLDER LORRAINE:
Coming, Dave.
Come on, Dad,
we're not gonna hold
your reservations
all day.
OLDER GEORGE: I can't
find my glasses.
Lorraine,
have you seen
my glasses?
They're in your
suede jacket, honey.
Marty, what's wrong?
We thought you
went to the lake.
You wore that
to the lake?
Thank God you guys
are all back to normal.
Marty, who are you
supposed to be?
Clint Eastwood?
(LAUGHING)
Right.
I gotta go get Jennifer.
I really like
that hat, Marty.
(ENGINE STARTING)
Thanks, Biff.
Jennifer.
Jen.
(MOANS)
Marty.
I had the worst
nightmare.
Marty, that dream
I had is so real.
It was about
the future.
About us.
And you got fired.
Wait a minute.
What do you mean
I got fired?
MARTY: "Hilldale."
Hilldale!
This is where we live.
I mean, this is where
we're going to live.
Someday.
Marty, it was a dream,
wasn't it?
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(LOUD ROCK MUSIC PLAYING)
(LAUGHING)
Hey.
The big M.
How's it hanging, McFly?
Hey, Needles.
Nice set of wheels.
Let's see what
she can do.
Next green light.
No, thanks.
What's the matter?
Chicken?
BOY: (LAUGHING)
Chicken McFly.
Whoo!
(EXCLAIMING)
Marty, don't.
Grab hold of something.
Come on!
Get on!
(ENGINE REVVING)
Yeah, go! Go, go, go!
(ALL SHOUTING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
(EXCLAIMS)
JENNIFER: Did you
do that on purpose?
Yeah, you think
I'm stupid enough
to race that asshole?
(HORN HONKING)
(TIRES SCREECHING)
Jeez! I would have
hit that Rolls-Royce.
It erased.
You're right.
There's not
much left.
Doc's never
coming back.
I'm sure gonna
miss him, Jen.
(TRAIN CROSSING BELL CLANGING)
What the hell?
(GASPS)
Doc!
Marty!
Doc! Doc!
Marty,
it runs on steam!
Meet the family.
Clara, you know.
Hi, Marty!
Ma'am!
These are our boys.
Jules and Verne.
(LAUGHS)
Boys,
this is Marty
and Jennifer.
Doc, I thought I'd
never see you again.
You can't keep
a good scientist down.
After all,
I had to come back
for Einstein,
and, well,
I didn't want you to
be worried about me.
Oh!
I brought you
a little souvenir.
It's great, Doc.
Thanks.
Dr. Brown,
I brought this note
back from the future,
and now it's erased.
Of course
it's erased.
But what does
that mean?
It means your future
hasn't been written yet.
No one's has.
Your future is
whatever you make it.
So make it a good one,
both of you.
We will, Doc!
Stand back!
All right, boys,
buckle up!
Hey, Doc,
where are you going now?
Back to the future?
No, already been there.
(WHISTLE BLOWING)